# **KENNIS KEYING CHEN**

### MULTI-DISCIPLINARY DESIGNER

Kennis is a designer who could translate empathy, concepts and aesthetics into designs, she has abundant experience of working in different positions. She is specializing in Concept Developing, Critical Thinking, Model Making and Storytelling. Along with her journey, Kennis is an explorer who driven and motivated by possibilities and challenges ahead, not only benefits from her distinctive view with dual culture perspective and also keen on learning new media to make the place we live in better & better. She prides herself in the quality and details of work.



### **SKILL**

### Software

MacOS Office Suites Microsoft Office Suites InDesign | Photoshop | Illustrator Premiere | Final Cut Pro Rhinoceros | Keyshot | AutoCad Solidthinking Evolve

### Design Skill

Concept Developing | Sketching Creativity | Illutration | Moodboard Product Detailing | Lithography Interior Planning

### LANGUAGE

Professional Proficiency English Mandarin Native Proficiency Cantonese Native Proficiency

### **EDUCATION**

PARSONS SCHOOL OF DESIGN 2019-Present

Design & Technology (MFA)

KENDALL COLLEGE OF ART & **DESIGN (KCAD)** 2014-2018

Furniture Design (BFA) Interior Design Minor

**GUANGZHOU ACADEMY OF FINE** ARTS (GAFA) 2012-2014

Art History (BFA)

## HONOR

- Graduated with Honors 2018
- Dean's List 2014-2018
- Portfolio Scholarship 2014-2018 AHFA Foundation Grants
- GR Furniture Designers 2016-2018 Endowed Scholarship
- Tim Roberts Endowed 2017-2018 Scholarship
- T. J. Amick Memorial 2016-2017 Scholarship
- Winter Wonderland 2014 Window Competition Top10

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **DIMENSIONS FURNITURE**

Product Designer | Indianapolis, USA | 7/2018 - 5/2019

- Part of the product development team, done ideas & digital modeling.
- Worked with buyers for developing furniture from different price points.
- Designed carton layouts for flat pack furniture, communicated with factories.
  In charge of drawing assembly instruction for products.
- Participated Drew Barrymore & Walmart Collaboration "Flower" Collection.

#### WAYFAIR INC.

Freelance Interior Designer | Indianapolis, USA | 7/2018 - 7/2019

- Part of the design service team, provided interior planning for clients.
- Communicated with clients from different backgrounds through the process.
- Created moodboard, selected items in clients' budget.

#### KCAD INTERNATIONAL STUDENT UNION

Finance Director/Presidum Member | Grand Rapids, USA | 2014 - 2018

- In charge of financial support, helped group leaders to determine the budget.
- Participated and organized 3 times of cultural festival with 500+ participants.

### KINDEL FURNITURE

Design Intern | Grand Rapids, USA | 2/2015 - 5/2015

- Created CAD drawing for new category.
- Participated and organized invitation for upcoming furniture trade market.
- Organized material samples for display into categories.

#### THE 6TH ART PRIZE

Volunteer | Grand Rapids, USA | 9/2014

- In charge of gallery guide and maintain order.
- Distributed brochures for exhibitions, welcomed audience.

### LIAO BINGXIONG FOUNDATION

Volunteer | Guangzhou, China | 7/2013 - 7/2014

- In charge of translating Cantonese into Mandarin for Liao Bingxiong's work.
  Participated and edited the 10th Anniversary Collection.

#### GAFA ART HISTORY DEPARTMENT

Office Assistant | Guangzhou, China | 6/2012 - 6/2014

- Conducted and organized orientation, activities and recruitment.
- Participated and edited the School History Collection.
- Collected information and communicated with alumnus.
- In charge of sorting and collating documentation & archives for seniors.